Local 1199 Guild Division Records 5206-G
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Guild Division Records
1963-1972
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU)
RWDSU Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union
5206-G
7.11 cubic feet
7.1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records of the National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees document the evolution of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store drugstore local, representing pharmacists and drug clerks in New York City, into an international union of non-professional and professional workers in voluntary and non-profit health institutions, including hospitals, clinics and nursing homes, as well as drugstores.
6694252
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 05, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Between 1933 and 1957, 1199 functioned as a drugstore local with its membership growing to 5,000 workers employed in independent and chain drugstores throughout the New York metropolitan area. With its success in organizing workers in Montefiore Hospital in New York City, the union began a massive campaign to organize workers in voluntary and non-profit hospitals in the New York area, a large proportion of whom were black or Hispanic.
In 1973, the national union was established with locals in other states, including Pennsylvania, Maryland, South and North Carolina, Connecticut, New Jersey, and Massachusetts. The union combined organizing efforts with civil rights organizations, in an effort to achieve mutual political goals. Throughout the period of these records, the union was led by Leon Davis (president of Local 1199 and of the national union) whose administration guided the union's political and social activities.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5206: Local 1199 Records 5206-D: Local 1199 Drug Division Records 5206-PR: Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records 5206-S: Local 1199 Executive Secretary Moe Foner Records 5206-X: Local 1199 Clippings and News Releases 5457: Mark Lillian Collection of Roosevelt Hospital (NYC) vs. Local 1199, 1962 Representational Dispute Documents 5510: Local 1199 Records 5520m: "Building a Union in the Hospitals: the Organization of Local 1199 at Montefoire Hospital, 1948-1958" Manuscript 5525: Local 1199 Additional Files 5651: Local 1199 Additional Records 5768: Sidney Cahn Collection of League of Voluntary Hospitals & Homes of New York vs. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union Arbitration Files 5680 OH: Local 1199 Oral History Project 5854: Local 1199 Additional Records 5871: Local 1199 Additional Records 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5933: Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union News files 5933 P: Local 1199 Photograph Files 5938: Local 1199 Leon Davis Additional Papers 5945: Local 1199 Additional Records 5948: Local 1199 (Rochester, N.Y.) Records 5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos 5984 AV: Local 1199 Additional Videos 6016: Local 1199 National Benefit and Pension Fund Records 6062: Paul Friedman Collection of National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Local 1199 Miscellany 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6140 P: Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 6209 AV: 1199SEIU Audio-Visual Materials 6209 PUBS: Local 1199 Publications 6281m: Local 1199 Biography files 6347: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Records 6347 PUBS: 1199SEIU United Healthcare Workers East Publications
Health facilities -- Labor unions -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Health facilities -- United States; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees. District 1199; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Employees Union (New York, N.Y.)
6694252
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Albert Einstein College Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bellevue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bellevue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bellevue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Beth Abraham Home and Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Beth Abraham Home and Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Beth Abraham Home and Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Beth Abraham Home and Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Beth Israel Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Beth Israel Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Beth Israel Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Beth Israel Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Bird S. Coler, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Booth Memorial, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Bronx Eye and Ear Infirmary, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bronx-Lebanon Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Bronx-Lebanon Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bronx-Lebanon Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bronx-Lebanon Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Brookdale Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Brookdale Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Brookdale Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Brooklyn-Cumberland Medical Center, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospital, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Brooklyn Hospital, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Brooklyn Jewish Hospital, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Brooklyn Jewish Hospital, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Brooklyn Psychiatric Center, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Brooklyn Psychiatric Center, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Charles Drew Center, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Columbia University, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Columbia University, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Columbia University, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Columbus Hospital, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Community General Hospital, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Community Hospital of Brooklyn, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Community Hospital of Brooklyn, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Community Hospital of Brooklyn, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Community Hospital of Brooklyn, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Community Service Society, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Coney Island Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Coney Island Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Coney Island Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Coney Island Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Cumberland Hospital, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Cumberland Hospital, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Daughters of Israel, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Daughters of Israel, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Daughters of Israel, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Daughters of Jacob, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Daughters of Jacob, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Daughters of Jacob, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Eastern Long Island Hospital, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Eastern Long Island Hospital, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Elmhurst, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Elmhurst, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Elmhurst, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Evangelical Home, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Flower-Fifth Avenue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Flower-Fifth Avenue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Flower-Fifth Avenue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Flower-Fifth Avenue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Flower-Fifth Avenue Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Flushing Hospital, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Flushing Hospital, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Flushing Hospital, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Flushing Hospital, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Fordham-Misericordia Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- French Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- French Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- French Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- French Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Goldwater Memorial Hospital, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Gouverneur Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Gouverneur Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Gouverneur Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Gouverneur Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Gracie Square, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Greenpoint Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Greenpoint Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Greenpoint Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Greenpoint Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Harlem Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Harlem Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Harlem Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Harlem Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Haym Salomon Home, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Haym Salomon Home, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Haym Salomon Home, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Haym Salomon Home, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Hempstead, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Jewish Chronic Hospital, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Jewish Chronic Hospital, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Jewish Hospital and Medical Center, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Jewish Hospital and Medical Center, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Jewish Institute for Geriatric Care, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Jewish Long Island, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Jewish Memorial, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Joint Diseases Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Joint Diseases Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Joint Diseases Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Joint Diseases Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Kingsbrook Jewish Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Kingsbrook Jewish Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Knickerbocker Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Knickerbocker Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Knickerbocker Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Knickerbocker Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- League for Practical Nurses, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Lemberger Hospital, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 1a)
- Lincoln Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Lincoln Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Lincoln Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Lincoln Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Long Island Jewish Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Long Island Jewish Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Long Island Jewish Hospital, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Lutheran Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Lutheran Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Lutheran Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Lutheran Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Lutheran Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Maimonides Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Maimonides Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Maimonides Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Maimonides Medical Center, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Mannasset Hospital, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Martin Luther King Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Metropolitan Hospital, 1969-1972 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Montefoire Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Montefoire Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Montefoire Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Montefoire Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Montefoire Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Morris J. Bernstein Institute, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Morrisania City Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Morrisania City Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Morrisania City Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- New York Infirmary, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- New York Infirmary, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- New York Infirmary, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- New York Infirmary, 1964-1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- New York University Medical Center, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- New York University Medical Center, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- New York University Medical Center, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- New York University Medical Center, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Newark Beth Israel Hospital, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Northside Center, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Parkway Hospital, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Peninsula General Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Peninsula General Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Peninsula General Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Peninsula General Hospital, 1967-1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Presbyterian Hospital, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Public Health Research Institute, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Queens Hospital Center Affiliate, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Queens Hospital Center Affiliate, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Queens Hospital Center Affiliate, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Queens Hospital Center Affiliate, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Richmond Memorial Hospital, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Roosevelt Hospital, 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- St. Barnabas Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- St. Francis Hospital, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- St. John's Episcopal Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- St. John's Episcopal Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- St. John's Episcopal Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- St. John's Episcopal Hospital, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- St. Luke's Hospital, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- St. Mary's Hospital, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- St. Michael's Hospital, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Sephardic Home, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Staten Island Hospital, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Southside Hospital, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Syosset Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Trafalgar Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Trafalgar Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Trafalgar Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Trafalgar Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- United Odd Fellows Home, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- United Odd Fellows Home, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- United Odd Fellows Home, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Unity Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Unity Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Unity Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Unity Hospital, 1964-1972 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Vassar Brothers Hospital, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Yeshiva University, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Yeshiva University, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Yeshiva University, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Chapter Membership Meeting Reports, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Chapter Membership Meeting Reports, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Correspondence-Miscellaneous, 1964-1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Delegate Newsletter, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- General, 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Grievance Reports, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Grievance Reports, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Pharmacy poster (Box 15)